<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rohilaHarsh</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/</link><description>Recent content on rohilaHarsh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 08:01:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rohilaharsh.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Top 10 Tools I found productive when working with TypeScript</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/productive-js-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 08:01:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/productive-js-tools/</guid><description>There are lots of software tools freely available to use. Some of them highly impacts the way we work, and they can let us do more in less time
If you are someone working with TypeScript/JavaScript, checkout the following productivity tools if they work for you
1. Volta Are you telling your team to install a particular version of Node.js for a project? Or working with multiple projects requiring different Node.</description></item><item><title>Stencil for React Devs</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/stencil-for-react-devs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 08:21:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/stencil-for-react-devs/</guid><description>What is Stencil? Stencil is one of the best tools out there to build web components. The following is from Stencil’s official website
Stencil is a compiler that generates Web Components (more specifically, Custom Elements). Stencil combines the best concepts of the most popular frameworks into a simple build-time tool.
Comparison With React There are many things common in Stencil and React
JSX/TSX templates Stencil also uses JSX templates with few differences compared to React</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/about/</guid><description>Hi
I am Harsh Rohila, working as a Software Engineer
This blog is to share what I learned from my experience in this field.
My Experience I started with learning JavaScript and got to work on an Ember.js project. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know Ember.js it is an underrated frontend framework with principle of convention over configuration
After learning Ember.js, I started looking into other Frontend frameworks. Now I use Stencil.js to build web components</description></item></channel></rss>