<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on rohilaHarsh</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on rohilaHarsh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 09:29:13 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementing YouTube's feature - Play video on thumbnail hover</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/video-play-on-hover/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 09:29:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/video-play-on-hover/</guid><description>Today I implemented a feature of YouTube in my app . This feature will play video on hover of the thumbnail of a video.
Code Changes This commit is having the changes I did for implementing this feature.
Implementation Explaination I have used template like below for showing thumbnail card for videos &amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;card&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img class=&amp;#34;thumbnail&amp;#34; src={this.thumbnail}&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/img&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;video-preview&amp;#34;&amp;gt; {this.stream &amp;amp;&amp;amp; this.showVideoPreview &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ( &amp;lt;video-player sources={this.stream.sources} muted={true}&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/video-player&amp;gt; )} &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; In this template, &amp;ldquo;stream&amp;rdquo; is the video stream data used for playing videos, &amp;ldquo;muted&amp;rdquo; is used to play videos in mute by default.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes, using TypeScript</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 09:29:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/kubernetes/</guid><description>At my work, I learned Kubernetes and used that to migrate an old API project. It required lots of learning and research. In this post, I will share my learnings, so it can help others getting started with Kubernetes.
Kubernetes Cluster To use Kubernetes, we need a Kubernetes Cluster. I used AWS EKS for that. EKS can be used with AWS Fargate and EC2 instances. I went with Fargate. To create most things in AWS, AWS CDK can be used.</description></item><item><title>Callback Pattern</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/callback-pattern/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 09:29:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/callback-pattern/</guid><description>A different view of Functions People experienced in JS have a different view of functions compared to people new to JS coming from background of C, C++, Java.
Consider below JS function
let sum = function (a, b) { return a + b } The idea of storing a function in variable might seem weird to new JS developers, but this is a powerful feature of JS. This can be used in interesting ways.</description></item><item><title>RxJS Zip Operator Use Case</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/rxjs-zip-operator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 09:29:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/rxjs-zip-operator/</guid><description>I like writing RxJS code. It makes it easy to combine async logic with sync and it treats both of these things in same way.
Recently, at my work, I used zip operator for the first time. I used this in a NestJS project. This operator is not commonly used. In this post I will share for which problem I used it and how it was used.
The Problem I have an array of input objects.</description></item><item><title>Animation on Scroll with Intersection Observer API</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/intersection-observer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 09:29:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/intersection-observer/</guid><description>Recently, in one of my websites I implemented below type of animation on scroll. Try scrolling below list of cards. Notice that the cards are animating only when they are in view.
In this post I am going to explain its implementation. It&amp;rsquo;s using one of the Browser APIs, called Intersection Observer API.
What is Intersection Observer API? The Intersection Observer API is an API using which we can run a callback if an element intersects any other element.</description></item><item><title>Using TypeScipt for Scripts and IAAC</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/using-ts-for-scripts-and-iaac/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 20:07:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/using-ts-for-scripts-and-iaac/</guid><description>I am using TypeScript for everything I code, Frontend, Backend, AWS Infrastructure as Code (IAAC), and writing scripts. In this post, I will cover less common scenarios of writing scripts and IAAC in TypeScript.
Why use TypeScript for writing Scripts? This is for people who are familiar with TS and don&amp;rsquo;t know bash, to write scripts.
If you are using TS for your daily work, it would be easier to use the same language for scripts for automation as there is no context switching to another language.</description></item><item><title>Using RxJS with Stencil.js</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/rxjs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 09:29:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/rxjs/</guid><description>RxJS is mainly popular with Angular Developers. In this post, I am going to share how I used RxJS with Stencil.js to build reactive components.
Ideas in this post should be applicable to other Frontend techs too.
This post assumes familiarity with RxJS, check my RxJS basics post for that
Show me the code Reactive components A frontend component will usually have some state, let&amp;rsquo;s represent that state by state$ (pronounced as state stream).</description></item><item><title>RxJS Basics</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/rxjs-basics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 09:29:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/rxjs-basics/</guid><description>Learning RxJS was difficult for me, but it was worth it as it simplifies implementing many complex async features in a Frontend app.
Now I think of it, its not that difficult. In this post I will try to simplify learning RxJS. I am using RxJS with Stencil.js, so I will cover what is essential in using it in a Frontend app. Let&amp;rsquo;s begin.
Reactive Programming RxJS is a library using which we can do Reactive programming.</description></item><item><title>Using Glimmer.js v1 in Production</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/glimmerjs-v1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 09:29:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/glimmerjs-v1/</guid><description>TL;DR If you are using Glimmer.js v1 in production like me, you can find this npm package which I published, useful. Its original repo is archived, so I forked and started maintaining separate npm package. For now, I only did one change to use the latest TypeScript features with Glimmer.js v1
What is Glimmer.js Glimmer.js is a lightweight frontend tool like Preact to build components.
Why we are using it? We had a requirement to convert an Ember.</description></item><item><title>JavaScript Prototype Easy Explaination</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/js-prototype/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:07:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/js-prototype/</guid><description>JavaScript prototype is an interesting feature which I read about many times, but I forget that easily, because of so many similar terms and concepts. This post aims to be an easy explanation for Prototype feature
Why Prototype? For using inheritance
What is it? It&amp;rsquo;s a hidden property (denoted by [[Prototype]]) in every object. When a property (not present in an object) is accessed, JS tries to find it in that object&amp;rsquo;s Prototype.</description></item><item><title>A not so popular class pattern - TypeScript</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/not-so-popular-oop-pattern/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 09:29:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/not-so-popular-oop-pattern/</guid><description>TypeScript is a flexible language. Using it you can write code doing the same thing in multiple ways. This can be considered as both disadvantage and advantage of the language.
Disadvantage being, people need to know so many things to understand variety of codebases.
I consider this as a good thing, as it offers developers so many ways to express what code is doing. Developers can use that to make code more readable according to different situations.</description></item><item><title>Clean Code Book Summary</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/clean-code-learnings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 08:41:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/clean-code-learnings/</guid><description>The book Clean Code by Robert C Martin, changed the way I think about and write code.
Why Clean Code? Have a look at the image below which is from the book
I love this image. It clearly shows the frustration of developers reading bad code.
Clean code leads to code which other developers can understand quickly. Developers can easily change code without breaking any existing features.
A code which takes more time to make changes and is difficult to understand will decrease the team productivity</description></item><item><title>Top 10 Tools I found productive when working with TypeScript</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/productive-js-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 08:01:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/productive-js-tools/</guid><description>There are lots of software tools freely available to use. Some of them highly impacts the way we work, and they can let us do more in less time
If you are someone working with TypeScript/JavaScript, checkout the following productivity tools if they work for you
1. Volta Are you telling your team to install a particular version of Node.js for a project? Or working with multiple projects requiring different Node.</description></item><item><title>Stencil for React Devs</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/stencil-for-react-devs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 08:21:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/stencil-for-react-devs/</guid><description>What is Stencil? Stencil is one of the best tools out there to build web components. The following is from Stencil’s official website Stencil is a compiler that generates Web Components (more specifically, Custom Elements). Stencil combines the best concepts of the most popular frameworks into a simple build-time tool.
Comparison With React There are many things common in Stencil and React
JSX/TSX templates Stencil also uses JSX templates with few differences compared to React</description></item></channel></rss>