<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on rohilaHarsh</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on rohilaHarsh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 08:41:09 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Clean Code Book Summary</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/clean-code-learnings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 08:41:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/clean-code-learnings/</guid><description>The book Clean Code by Robert C Martin, changed the way I think about and write code.
Why Clean Code? Have a look at the image below which is from the book
I love this image. It clearly shows the frustration of developers reading bad code.
Clean code leads to code which other developers can understand quickly. Developers can easily change code without breaking any existing features.
A code which takes more time to make changes and is difficult to understand will decrease the team productivity</description></item><item><title>Top 10 Tools I found productive when working with TypeScript</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/productive-js-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 08:01:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/productive-js-tools/</guid><description>There are lots of software tools freely available to use. Some of them highly impacts the way we work, and they can let us do more in less time
If you are someone working with TypeScript/JavaScript, checkout the following productivity tools if they work for you
1. Volta Are you telling your team to install a particular version of Node.js for a project? Or working with multiple projects requiring different Node.</description></item><item><title>Stencil for React Devs</title><link>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/stencil-for-react-devs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 08:21:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohilaharsh.in/posts/stencil-for-react-devs/</guid><description>What is Stencil? Stencil is one of the best tools out there to build web components. The following is from Stencil’s official website
Stencil is a compiler that generates Web Components (more specifically, Custom Elements). Stencil combines the best concepts of the most popular frameworks into a simple build-time tool.
Comparison With React There are many things common in Stencil and React
JSX/TSX templates Stencil also uses JSX templates with few differences compared to React</description></item></channel></rss>